It's amazing, Ruiko.
すごいよ涙子
I could barely lift a paper cup!
私紙コップ持ち上げるのがやっとだったのに
Are you okay?
Ruiko?
涙子
What should I do?! This is a special ability!
どうしよう　能力だ
Akemi!
アケミ　よくも落としてくれたわね
Thanks for dropping me!
Cut it out!
悪いな
重い
This ability might not be much compared to Shirai-san or Misaka-san's ability.
白井さんや御坂さんに比べたら ささやかな力だけど
This ability might not look like anything to others, but...
他人から見れば　到底ことない力だけど
I became an ability user!
あたし　能力者に　なったんだ
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
未来さえ置き去りにして
限界など知らない　意味無い！
この能力が光散らす　その先に遥かな想いを
チカラ
歩いてきた　この道を　振り返ることしか
出来ないなら…今ここで全てを壊せる
暗闇に堕ちる街並み
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
加速するその痛みから
誰かをきっと守れるよ
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
身体中を　光の速さで　駆け巡った　確かな予感
掴め！望むものなら残さず　輝ける自分らしさで
信じてるよ　あの日の誓いを
この瞳に光る涙　それさえも強さになるから
Estimated time until completion 2 Seconds...
Estimated time until completion 1 Second...
Saved
Finished.
完了っと
Just listening to this causes you to level up...
でも　これを聞くだけでレベルアップなんて
Is it really a possibility?
本当にそんなことあるんですかね
According to a benevolent tip off, that's what they said.
善意の情報提供者はそう言っていましたわ
I don't really believe it, but...
正直　眉唾というか
Oh but if I used this and become an ability user greater than Shirai-san...
でもこれを使って 白井さん以上の能力者になったら
I could do stuff like this and that and get revenge for all I've suffered.
今までの仕返しにあんなことやこんなことを
All your thoughts are open.
思考がただ漏れですのよ
If you want to get revenge on me then sure.
私に恨みを晴らしたいのでしたら　是非
I'm lying!
嘘です　嘘ですよ
It was a lie!
Your mobile! Your mobile is ringing!
携帯　携帯鳴ってますよ
Yes.
はい　はい　分かりました
Yes, I understand.
It looks like another student is going violent again.
また学生が暴れているらしいですの
Uiharu, call Kiyama-sensei.
初春は木山先生に連絡を
Understood.
分かりました
Yes, the actual file has arrived.
現物は届いてるよ
Is it really possible to increase your ability by using just music?
音楽ソフトで能力を上げるっなんてこと　可能なんでしょうか
Hmm... that's difficult.
難しいね
If it was the Testament, then I don't know...
<Testament>
学習装置ならいざしらず
Testament?
<Testament>
学習装置そういう装置があるんですか
There's a machine like that?
Oh...
あー　はい　はい
Yes.
I see.
そうですか
Thank you very much.
いろいろとありがとうございました
Are we following a wrong lead thinking it's just music?
やっぱり　音楽ソフトなんて見当違いなんでしょうか
Oh, hello, Saten-san?
もしもし佐天さん
The number you called is somewhere without a signal or is turned off and-
おかけになった電話は電波の届かない場所にあるか
電源が入っていないため　かかり…
How do you like my power?
どうだ　俺の力は
Another Level Upper?
<Level Upper>
また幻想御手ですの
What are you?
なんだいあんた
10 years too early to screw with me!
あたしとやろうなんて
十年早い
So you're 10 years older than me?
十歳も年上でしたの
My,
俺の
power.
この力を
It's enough!
もういい加減にしてほしいですわ
It's going to sting a bit.
はい　ちょっと沁みますよ
You're getting more wounds every day.
日に日に生傷が増えていきますね
It can't be helped.
仕方ないですわ
<Level Upper>
幻想御手の使用者が増えてるんですもの
There are more and more Level Upper users.
I have no idea how widespread it's become.
どれくらい広まってるのか　想像もつきませんね
There no use whining.
泣き言を言っても　始まりませんわよ
Anyhow, there's three things we should do:
とにかく　私たちが為すべきことは三つ
Stop the spread of Level Upper,
<Level Upper>
幻想御手拡散の阻止と
Recover the users who have become unconscious,
昏睡した使用者の恢復
And...
<Level Upper>
そして　幻想御手開発者の検挙
Capture the inventor of Level Upper.
We're going to find whoever spread this throughout the internet...
これを開発し　ネットに広めた何者かを必ず見つけ出して
and make them confess!
目論見を吐かせてやりますわ
All right, let's finish up with the treatment.
さ　先に手当てしちゃいましょう
You want Misaka-san to wrap it around you, right?
本当は御坂さんに巻いてほしいんじゃないんですか
I can't have Onee-sama see me like this.
お姉樣に私のこんな姿を見せるわけにはいきませんわ
Don't worry.
大丈夫ですよ　誰も見たくないですから
No one wants to see you period.
Hey!
オッス　私も何か手伝えることあった…
Is there anything I can help with-
Good evening, Onee-sama.
ご　ご機嫌よう　お姉樣
Are you making progress with the investigation?
で　進んでるの　捜査のほう
Well...
それが
According to Kiyama-sensei,
木山先生の話では
there's a special machine called a Testament, which can transmit a great deal of electrical signals to the brain in a short period of time.
短期間に大量の電気的情報を脳に入力するための
<Testament>
学習装置という特殊な装置もあるそうですの
It can function via any of the five senses - sight, hearing, taste, smell, and touch.
でも　それは視覚　聴覚　味覚　嗅覚　触覚の五感すべてに働きかけるもので
Level Upper itself is only a musical program.
<Level Upper>
幻想御手はただの音楽ソフト
It operates only via the auditory organs.
聴覚作用だけね
When we investigated the rooms of the victims who fell unconscious,
植物状態になった被害者の部屋を捜索しても
we found nothing except that song.
あの曲のデータ以外 何も見つからないんです
Hot water room
Oh...
仮の話だけどさ
This is just some speculation on my part, but...
I wouldn't rule out the possibility that the song can affect all five senses.
曲自体に五感に働きかける作用がある可能性はないかな
What do you mean?
どういう意味ですの
Don't you remember the conversation we had when we were eating shaved ice?
前に　かき氷食べた時の会話　覚えてない
Hmm...
Uhh, we were going to taste each other's?
えっと　食べ比べ
No not that one.
いや　そっちでなく
あっ　共感覚性
Synesthesia!
What's that?
なんですか
It's synesthesia!
共感覚性ですの
Obtaining more than one sensory input from a single stimulus!
一つの刺激で複数の感覚を得ることですわ
Or, in other words, stimulating one sensory organ will, in turn...
ある種の方法で感覚を刺激することによって
別の感覚も刺激されることよ
stimulate another one.
That would mean...
つまり　音で五感を刺激し
That they're using sound to stimulate all five senses in order to achieve the same effect as Testament?
<Testament>
学習装置と同じような効果を出していると
That is a possibility.
その可能性はあるな
I see. I didn't think of that.
なるほど　見落としていた
I'd like to ask you to look further into this line of reasoning.
その線で調査をお願いしたいのですが
Yes.
We should be able to get permission to use the Tree Diagram for this.
そういうことなら
<Tree Diagram>
樹形図の設計者の許可も下りるだろう
Tree Diagram?
<Tree Diagram>
樹形図の設計者
It's the finest supercomputer in Academy City! It'll spit out results in an instant!
学園都市一のスーパーコンピュータなら　すぐですね
I'll tell you when we have results.
結果が出たら知らせるよ
Then can I head over to where you are now?
じゃ　今からそっちに行ってもいいですか
I want to see the Tree Diagram in use!
<Tree Diagram>
樹形図の設計者を使うところを　私も見てみたいんです
Yes, that's fine.
はっ　かまわんよ
How's this!?
どうよ
I can do this with only like, five days of practice!
四五日練習しただけでもうこれだよ
Me too!
私だって
You're all great!
みんなすごーい
Maybe I should at least tell Uiharu.
やっぱ　初春にだけは教えようかな
But she might get mad...
でも　怒られちゃうかな
Akemi?
アケミ　アケミちゃん
Akemi-chan?
What happened?
どうしたの　アケミちゃん
Akemi-chan!
Akemi!
アケミ　アケミちゃん　しっかりして
Akemi-chan!
Are you all right?
Pull yourself together!
大丈夫
Akemi-chan!
アケミちゃん
Saten Ruiko
佐天さん　心配してたんですよ
Oh, Saten-san?
I was worried about you.
You're acting unfriendly at school, and you won't return my calls...
学校でも余所余所しいし
電話しても着信拒否だし
She went unconscious.
…れちゃった
What?
はい
Akemi suddenly lost consciousness.
アケミが急に倒れちゃったの
えっ
Huh?
I didn't know that using the Level Upper caused loss of consciousness...
<Level Upper>
幻想御手を使ったら倒れちゃうなんて
あたし知らなくて
Why is this happening?
なんでこんなことに
This wasn't what I wanted...
あたし　そんなつもりじゃ…
C-Calm down...
おちっ 落ち着いて
Just explain everything from the beginning.
ゆっくり最初から
I got the Level Upper, but...
<Level Upper>
幻想御手を手に入れちゃったんだけど
I was hesitant, since you had mentioned arresting those in possession of it.
所有者を捕まえるっていうから
And yet I couldn't just throw it away.
でも　捨てられなくて
Because... Akemi and the others said they wanted to use it.
<Level Upper>
それで　アケミたちが幻想御手がほしいって
No, that's not it... I was just scared to use it by myself.
ううん　違う
本当は　一人で使うのが怖かっただけ
Anyway, where are you?
とにかく　いまどこですか
Am I going to lose consciousness too?
あたしも倒れちゃうのかな
What if I never wake up again?
そしたら　もう二度と起きられないのかな
I hated myself because I had no abilities.
あたし　何の力もない自分が嫌で
And I couldn't stop myself from admiring those who had them.
でも　どうしても憧れは捨てられなくて
Mommy...
ママ
Hmm? What?
えっ　何ですか
Does being a Level Zero mean that you're defective?
<Level 0>
無能力者って欠陥品なのかな
What are you talking about?
何を
I went so far as to cheat my way into having an ability. That's why I'm being punished now.
それがズルして力を手にしようとしたから
罰が当たったのかな
Sticking my nose into dangerous business and getting the people around me involved in it too...
危ない物に手を出して
周りを巻き込んで
I'm...
あたし
You're fine!
大丈夫です　もし眠っちゃっても
Don't worry. I'll wake you up if you fall asleep.
私がすぐに起こしてあげます
I'll wake up Akemi-san and the rest, too!
佐天さんも　アケミさんも　他の眠っている人たちも
みんな
So... just let me take care of it!
だから　ドーンと私に任せちゃってください
I bet you'll say something like, "Gimme five more minutes..."
佐天さんきっと「あと五分だけ～」とか言っちゃいますよ
Uiharu...
初春
Saten-san, you aren't defective!
佐天さんは欠陥品なんかじゃありません
You might not be able to use an ability, but you always help me out!
能力なんか使えなくたって
いつもいつも私を引っ張ってくれるじゃないですか
It doesn't matter if you're a Level Zero or not! You are who you are, Saten-san!
力があってもなくても
佐天さんは佐天さんです
You're my best friend!
私の親友なんだから
So... so... don't say horrible things like that.
だから　だから
そんな悲しいこと　言わないで
Rely on Uiharu?
初春を頼れって言われてもね
Not just me!
私だけじゃないですよ
There are a ton of great people to rely on, like Misaka-san and Shirai-san.
御坂さんや白井さんや　他にもすごい人がいっぱい…
Yes, I know.
うん　分かってる
Thank you, Uiharu.
ありがとうね　初春
Sorry to cause you so much trouble.
迷惑ばっかかけてごめん
I'll leave the rest to you.
あと　よろしくね
Charm
佐天…さん
Silent
Majority
A Certain Scientific Railgun
沉默·
多数
So Saten-san used the Level Upper too.
<Level Upper>
佐天さんも幻想御手を
ええ　絶対データを解析して
Yes...
Uiharu took off for Kiyama-sensei's place. She said she was going to analyze the data and save Saten-san.
佐天さんを助けるんだって
初春は木山先生の所へ
I see.
そう
Can I talk to you for a while?
ちょっといい
What did you want to talk to me about?
お話って何ですの
Saten-san always has a charm with her, right?
佐天さん　御守り持ってたでしょう
Oh, the one she hangs on her bag.
ああ　いつも鞄にぶらさげてる
She said she got it from her mother,
あれね　お母さんにもらったんだって
before she came to Academy City.
学園都市に来る前に
She told you that?
そんな話をお姉樣に
Yes...
うん　たぶんいろいろ話したかったんだと思う
I think she wanted to talk to me about a lot of things.
But I...
<Level 5>
それなのに　私　超能力者とか言ってるけど
I might be a Level Five, but I'm no good with stuff like this...
そういうところは全然駄目だよね
お姉樣
Onee-sama...
If there's a hurdle in my path, I feel like I have to clear it.
私はさ　目の前にハードルが置かれたら
それを飛び越えないと気が進まない質だから
I'm only Level Five because of my personality.
<Level 5>
超能力者もその結果なだけで
I've never seen this as something special, really.
別にすごいとも思わなかった
But there are people out there who freeze in front of that hurdle.
でも　ハードルの前で立ち止まっちゃう人もいるんだよね
I never realized this.
そういう人がいるってことを　考えたこともなかった
I kept claiming that Level didn't matter.
<Level>
強さなんてどうでもいいんじゃない なんて
I was being really callous.
無神経な話だよね
So, please let me help you out with this investigation.
だから捜査に協力させて
Let me help you save Saten-san.
佐天さんを助けるためにも
分かりましたわ
I understand.
ありがとう　よろしくね
Thank you.
Please help me.
こ　こちらこそ
Me too.
Hey, can I have a minute?
ちょっといいかい
Oh, a real Gekota!
リアルゲコ太
Onee-sama, he isn't one!
お姉樣　違いますの
These are the brain wave patterns of the Level Upper victims.
<Level Upper>
これは幻想御手被害者の全脳波パターンだ
Brain waves generally differ by person; in other words, there's no common pattern.
脳波は個人個人で違うから
同じ波形なんてあり得ないんだね
However, all of the Level Upper victims indeed share one.
<Level Upper>
ところが　幻想御手被害者には
共通の脳波パターンがあることに気がついたんだよ
What do you mean?
どういうことですの
If one's brain was to be manipulated by another's brain wave pattern,
誰か他人の脳波パターンで　無理矢理脳が動かされているとしたら
then their body would suffer grave physical harm.
人体に湛えない影響も出るだろうね
So the victims fell unconscious after the Level Upper manipulated their brain waves directly?
<Level Upper>
幻想御手に無理矢理脳を弄られて
植物状態になったってこと
Who would do that? And why?
誰が　何のつもりで
I'm a doctor.
僕は医師だ
それを調べるのは　君たちの仕事だろう
You're the ones who are supposed to find the answers to those questions, right?
I see.
そうか　この間の彼女まで
That girl from last time, tooo...
It's my fault.
私のせいなんです
あまり自分を責めるもんじゃない
Don't blame yourself.
Why don't you take a break?
少し休みなさい
I'll make some coffee.
コーヒーでも入れてこよう
We don't have time to waste.
悠長なことをしている暇は
We haven't gotten the results of the analysis back yet.
解析結果まだ出ていないが
Your friend wouldn't like it if you were sick when she woke up.
お友達が目覚めた時に　君が倒れていては元も子もないだろう
It's fine.
大丈夫　最後はきっと上手くいくさ
It'll all work out in the end.
特定の人物の脳波バターンがはっきりしてるなら
If we know the brain wave of a specific person,
<Bank>
初春に書庫の検索をしてもらえば
we can have Uiharu search the bank for them.
あっ　って　初春がいないんですの
Oh, Uiharu isn't here.
That's right...
そうだった
まったく
Geez... What's with all the racket?
何を騒いでるの
Oh, Konori-senpai.
固法先輩
I see.
なるほど
If that's the case, then we should be granted permission to access the bank.
<Bank>
そういうことなら 書庫へのアクセスは認められるでしょね
What if their data isn't in the bank?
<Bank>
書庫にデータがなかったら
大丈夫ですわ　能力開発を受ける学生は勿論
Nah, don't worry.
It's got data from students who are Ability Users, sure,
病院の受診や職業を適性テストを受けた 大人のデータも保管されていますの
but it's also got data from adults who went to hospitals, took placement exams, et cetera.
<Level Upper>
でも　なんで幻想御手を使うと同一人物の脳波が組み込まれるのかな
But... Why would the Level Upper output the brain wave of a single person?
<Level>
しかも能力の強さが上がるなんて
And why would that make their Level increase?
さっぱり分かりませんわ
I don't get it.
コンピュータだって
Computers don't improve their performance through software.
あるソフトを使ったからって性能が格段に上がるわけじゃないわよね
However, connecting to a network is a different matter.
ネットワークに繋ぐならいざしらず
Connecting to a network improves performance?
ネットワークに繋ぐと性能が上がるんですか
個々の性能が上がるわけじゃないわ
Well, the performance of the individual units won't increase.
However, if you connect many computers in parallel, you can increase their overall processing power.
でも　幾つものコンピュータを並列に繋げば
演算能力が上がって
Oh... so you're saying that they were using Level Upper to build a cluster of brains?
そうか　もしかして
<Level Upper>
幻想御手を使って脳のネットワークを構築したんじゃん
That's a possibility.
可能性はあるわ
But how would they connect everyone's brains?
でも　どうやってみんなの脳を繋いでるんですか
考えられるとしたら
The only plausible explanation would be...
AIM拡散力場かな
The AIM diffusion field.
Ability Users emit power subconsciously.
能力者は無自覚に周囲に力を放出しているわ
If these fields were connected...
もしそれが繋がったら
Remember, though, they're subconscious.
でもあれは無意識間のことだし
私たちの脳はコンピュータって言えば
To continue the computer analogy, each of us is running a completely different operating system.
使ってるOSがばらばらだから
繋がっても意味ないんじゃないですか
Even if we're connected, there's no guarantee that it'll work.
Computer networks have computers with different operating systems.
コンピュータネットワークもOSはバラバラだし
使ってる言語だって違うわ
They use different languages too.
だけど　ネットワークが作れるのは
However, they share a common protocol, so they are all able to utilize the network.
プロトコルがあるからでしょ
A specific person's brain wave pattern is acting as the protocol here, then?
特定人物の脳波パターンが
プロトコルの役割をしているっていうんですの
あくまでも可能性だけど
Well, this is just speculation, like I said...
However, if they did manage to connect brains in parallel like that...
でも　そうやって脳を並列で繋げば
莫大の量の計算をすることができる
they'd be able to perform an enormous amount of calculations.
単独では弱い能力しか持っていない人でも
Even if they only have a weak ability on their own,
ネットワークと一体化することで
if they integrate with the network, the processing power of their ability will increase.
能力の処理能力が向上する
They'll also become able to use their ability more efficiently, due to sharing the logic patterns of similar types of abilities.
それに加えて
同系統の能力者の思考パターンが共有されることで
より効率的に能力を扱えるようになる
恐らく昏睡患者は
I assume that the unconscious victims are having all of their brains' processing power utilized by this "network," then.
脳の活動すべてをネットワークに使われているんじゃないかしら
The results came in!
出たわよ　脳波パターン一致率　９９パーセント
Their brain wave patterns are 99% similar!
This... this too...
これも　これも
Papers on synesthesia...
共感覚性の論文
Why?
なんで
Hey, that's not very nice.
いけないな
他人の研究成果を勝手に見ては
Going through other people's research efforts without permission, I mean.
T-This is...
これは
登録者名
Her registered name is...
Kiyama Harumi!
Name:
Kiyama Harumi
Place of employment:
Mizuho Agency Hospital
Special team on cerebral physiology
Ability level:
Ordinary researcher
木山春生
Uiharu-san!
初春さんが
What about her?
初春さんがどうしたの
She said she was going to Kiyama-sensei's place earlier!
さっきその木山先生の所へ行くって言って
What!?
何ですって
Uiharu!?
初春
The number you have called is currently out of range-
おかけになった電話は…
繋がらないんですの
We can't get in touch with her!
<Antiskill>
警備員に連絡
Call the Antiskills!
木山春生の身柄確報
Have them capture Kiyama Harumi!
ただし　人質がいる可能性あり
Tell them she might be taking hostages.
はい
Yes ma'am!
By the way, this has always bothered me...
ところで　以前から気になっていたんだが
What are the flowers on your head?
その頭の花は何だい
Do they have anything to do with your ability?
君の能力に関係があるのかな
I have no obligation to answer you.
お答えする義務はありません
More importantly, what is Level Upper?
<Level Upper>
そんなことより　幻想御手って何ですか
Why did you do this?
どうしてこんなことしたんですか
眠っている人たちはどうなるんです
What's going to happen to the victims?
One after another, eh?
矢継ぎ早だな
こっちの質問には答えてくれないのに
You're not doing a very good job of answering my question, though.
Increasing someone's Level, making them feel false happiness...
誰かの能力を引き上げて　糠喜びをさせて
What's so fun about that?
何がそんなに面白いんですか
Even Saten-san...
佐天さんだって　佐天さんだって
Heh.
他人の能力に興味はないんや
I have no interest in others' abilities.
My purpose is something much greater.
あたしの目的はもっと大きなものだ
I'm heading out too.
私も出るわ
一般人を巻き込みたくはないけど
I don't want to get commoners involved, but...
It'd be great if a Level Five could help out...
<Level 5>
超能力者なあなたが手伝ってくれたら
Onee-sama!
お姉樣
Uiharu is member of Judgment, after all.
<Judgement>
初春も風紀委員のはしくれですの
いざとなれば　自分の力で
When the going gets rough, she'll use her ability to...
Probably... somehow...
多分　何とか
運が良ければ
If she's lucky...
<Antiskill>
それに　一科学者にすぎない木山に警備員を退ける術はないかと
Furthermore, Kiyama is just a single scientist. There's no way she can beat all of the Antiskills!
何千人もの昏睡した能力者の命が握られてるのよ
She has the lives of thousands of unconscious Ability Users in her hands!
それに　なにか嫌な予感がするの
And... I have a bad feeling about this...
Then that's all the more reason!
<Judgement>
なら　なおのこと　ここは風紀委員の私が
A member of Judgment would...
Man, you're really persistent, trying to move in that state...
そんな体で動こうっての
お姉樣　気づかれて
Onee-sama, you realized it?
Of course.
当たり前でしょ
You're my kouhai,
アンタは私の後輩なんだから
so you can rely on me in times like this.
こんな時くらい お姉様に頼んなさい
Onee-sama...
お姉様
Heh.
A Certain Scientific Railgun
To be continued
待
续
Dear My Friend Every day & night
Always be with you
Dear My Friend every day & night
話しても　まだまだ　足りないまま
夕焼けが　街を染めてゆく
思うように　なかなか　いかない…って
気づいたら　一緒に　泣いていた
恋も　夢も　花も　虹も　風も
ぜんぶ掴もうよ
ダイジョウブ！　元気出して
私がそばにいるから
今日のミス　悔やむより　今　乗り越えて
ダイジョウブ！　迷わないで
まだ見ぬ未来へと向かって
ずっと　歩いてゆこう
Dear My Friend every day & night
Always be with you
Next Episode
Today was a lot of fun!
やー　今日も楽しかった
Kiyama-
sensei
木
山
老
师
予告も脱いで決めるとしよう
I guess I should undress for the preview.
So then next, episode...
さって次回
脱ぐな
Don't undress!
っていうかあんたは私が倒す
I'm gonna take care of you!